{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "101.What is the satellite which would be launched in partnership by Surrey Satellite Technology Ltd(SSTL) and Oxford Space Systems (OSS)?",
            "options": [
                "CarbSar",
                "Cryosat",
                "Spacesat",
                "UKSat"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "CarbSar"
        },
        {
            "question": "102.\u2018Cryosat\u2019 is a programme associated with which space agency?",
            "options": [
                "NASA",
                "ESA",
                "ISRO",
                "JAXA"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "ESA"
        },
        {
            "question": "104.Which is the first state to provide digital health cards for children?",
            "options": [
                "Uttar Pradesh",
                "Assam",
                "West Bengal",
                "Rajasthan"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Uttar Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "105.Galapagos Island is a UNESCO world nature heritage site situated in which country?",
            "options": [
                "South Africa",
                "Ecuador",
                "Sri Lanka",
                "Indonesia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ecuador"
        },
        {
            "question": "106.\u2018Kremlin\u2019 is used to refer the government of which country?",
            "options": [
                "Ukraine",
                "Russia",
                "Israel",
                "Iran"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Russia"
        },
        {
            "question": "107.Which institution is the regulator of insurance companies?",
            "options": [
                "RBI",
                "IRDAI",
                "PFRDA",
                "SEBI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IRDAI"
        },
        {
            "question": "108. ‘Saurona triangular and Saurona aurigera’, which were discovered recently, belong to which species?",
            "options": [
                "Snake",
                "Butterfly",
                "Spider",
                "Gecko"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Butterfly"
        },
        {
            "question": "109.\u2018Kh-47 Kinzhal\u2019 is the hypersonic missile unveiled by which country?",
            "options": [
                "Israel",
                "UAE",
                "Russia",
                "Ukraine"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Russia"
        },
        {
            "question": "110.Who is the author of the book titled \u2018Cyber Encounters\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Ashok Kumar",
                "Arun Kumar",
                "Alok Kumar",
                "Allwyn Kumar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ashok Kumar"
        },
        {
            "question": "111.Which Chief Minister conferred with the \u2018Bharat Ratna Dr Ambedkar Award\u2019 of BuddhanjaliResearch Foundation?",
            "options": [
                "Yogi Adityanath",
                "Naveen Patnaik",
                "Pinarayi Vijayan",
                "M K Stalin"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Yogi Adityanath"
        },
        {
            "question": "112.Which country launched the \u2018Naykap Gokab\u2019 platform?",
            "options": [
                "Nepal",
                "Bhutan",
                "Myanmar",
                "Bangladesh"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Bhutan"
        },
        {
            "question": "113.Centre for Innovation Incubation Research and Entrepreneurship (C-i2 RE) has beeninaugurated in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Tamil Nadu",
                "Telangana",
                "Gujarat",
                "Kerala"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Telangana"
        },
        {
            "question": "114.Which institution released a report titled \u2018Race to Net Zero\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "UNEP",
                "UNFCCC",
                "UN ESCAP",
                "WEF"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "UN ESCAP"
        },
        {
            "question": "115.Which state\/UT launched the \u2018Jaganannaku Chebudam programme\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Andhra Pradesh",
                "West Bengal",
                "Kerala",
                "Odisha"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Andhra Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "116.Cyber Surakshit Bharat is the initiative of which institution\/Union Ministry?",
            "options": [
                "NITI Aayog",
                "NASSCOM",
                "Ministry of Electronics and IT",
                "Ministry of Science and Technology"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ministry of Electronics and IT"
        },
        {
            "question": "117.Which country imposed the \u2018Title 42\u2019 order?",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "USA",
                "Ukraine",
                "Italy"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "118.Which institution released the \u2018Regional Economic Outlook: Middle East and Central Asia\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "World Bank",
                "IMF",
                "WEF",
                "ADB"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IMF"
        },
        {
            "question": "119.\u2018Science Media Communication Cell (SMCC)\u2019 is associated with which Union Ministry?",
            "options": [
                "Ministry of Communication",
                "Ministry of Science and Technology",
                "Ministry of Information and Broadcasting",
                "Ministry of External Affairs"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ministry of Science and Technology"
        },
        {
            "question": "120.\u2018Bandhavgarh Tiger Reserve (BTR)\u2019 is situated in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Gujarat",
                "Rajasthan",
                "Madhya Pradesh",
                "West Bengal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Madhya Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "121.Which space agency has developed the \u2018Aeolus Satellite\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "JAXA",
                "ISRO",
                "NASA",
                "ESA"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "ESA"
        },
        {
            "question": "122.Which company has launched \u2018Watsonx\u2019 AI and data platform?",
            "options": [
                "IBM",
                "Microsoft",
                "Google",
                "Apple"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IBM"
        },
        {
            "question": "123.India Post and Confederation of All India Traders (CAIT) partnered to operationalise whichportal?",
            "options": [
                "Craft India",
                "Bharat EMart",
                "India Mart",
                "Bharat Store"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Bharat EMart"
        },
        {
            "question": "124.\u2018Fakhar Zaman\u2019 who was named as the \u2018ICC Men's Player of the Month\u2019, is from which country?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Pakistan",
                "Bangladesh",
                "UAE"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Pakistan"
        },
        {
            "question": "125.Which country celebrates Victory Day to mark its victory over Nazi Germany during the SecondWorld War?",
            "options": [
                "France",
                "Russia",
                "USA",
                "China"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Russia"
        },
        {
            "question": "126.\u2018Seventeen-Point Agreement\u2019 is associated with which country?",
            "options": [
                "Japan",
                "Myanmar",
                "Tibet",
                "Nepal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Tibet"
        },
        {
            "question": "127.Jama Masjid, India\u2019s largest mosque, is situated in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Punjab",
                "New Delhi",
                "Uttarakhand",
                "Kerala"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "128.Siddheswara Temple, which was seen in the news, is located in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Andhra Pradesh",
                "Kerala",
                "West Bengal",
                "Assam"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Andhra Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "129.Sathyabhama Das Biju, who was seen in the news, is associated with which profession?",
            "options": [
                "Sports Person",
                "Biologist",
                "Politician",
                "Writer"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Biologist"
        },
        {
            "question": "130.The 35th Indo-Thai CORPAT was organised in which region?",
            "options": [
                "Andaman Sea",
                "Indian Ocean",
                "South China Sea",
                "Pacific Ocean"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Andaman Sea"
        },
        {
            "question": "131.Which institution introduced the \u2018Star Labelling Program\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "NITI Aayog",
                "Bureau of Energy Efficiency",
                "BARC",
                "BHEL"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Bureau of Energy Efficiency"
        },
        {
            "question": "132.\u2018Kaziranga Elevated Road project\u2019 is being constructed in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "West Bengal",
                "Assam",
                "Karnataka",
                "Odisha"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Assam "
        },
        {
            "question": "133.Fossil remains of a giant pilosaur was discovered in which country recently?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "China",
                "England",
                "Japan"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "134.The latest human genome, called \u2018Pangenome\u2019, is made using data from how many people?",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "7",
                "47",
                "74"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "47"
        },
        {
            "question": "135.\u2018OFDA 4000\u2019 is a state-of-art equipment, which has been procured by which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Arunachal Pradesh",
                "Jammu and Kashmir",
                "Rajasthan",
                "Gujarat"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Jammu and Kashmir"
        },
        {
            "question": "136.Which country is the host of the 6th Indian Ocean Conference (IOC)?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Sri Lanka",
                "Bangladesh",
                "Myanmar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Bangladesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "138.As per the \u2018Global Oil Infrastructure Tracker\u2019, what is the rank of India in the pipelines underconstruction category?",
            "options": [
                "Second",
                "Seventh",
                "Twelfth",
                "Fifteenth"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Second"
        },
        {
            "question": "139.Which institution released the \u2018Global Report on Internal Displacement 2023 (GRID-2023)\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "IDMC",
                "UNICEF",
                "World Bank",
                "WEF"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IDMC"
        },
        {
            "question": "140.Scientists have recently initiated a field trial to vaccinate which animals against \u2018Chlamydia\u2019diseases?",
            "options": [
                "Panda",
                "Koala",
                "Wolf",
                "Lions"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Koala"
        },
        {
            "question": "141.Which country has recently approved the \u2018Isaac River coal mine project\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Australia",
                "Russia",
                "India"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Australia"
        },
        {
            "question": "142.\u2018E-retrofitment\u2019, which was seen in the news, is associated with which field?",
            "options": [
                "Culture",
                "Electric Mobility",
                "Finance",
                "Sports"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Electric Mobility"
        },
        {
            "question": "143.Which cyclone has hit Myanmar and is one of the strongest storms to hit the region thiscentury?",
            "options": [
                "Cyclone Mocha",
                "Cyclone Myan",
                "Cyclone Mira",
                "Cyclone Moto"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Cyclone Mocha"
        },
        {
            "question": "144.Which institution launched the \u2018100 Days 100 Pays\u2019 campaign?",
            "options": [
                "RBI",
                "NPCI",
                "SEBI",
                "SBI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "RBI"
        },
        {
            "question": "145.\u2018AT2021lwx\u2019, which was seen in the news, is associated with which field?",
            "options": [
                "Computer Hardware",
                "Astronomy",
                "Finance",
                "Sports"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Astronomy"
        },
        {
            "question": "146.Which country has been hit by a large outbreak of the Moroccan locust in wheat plants?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Pakistan",
                "Afghanistan",
                "Myanmar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Afghanistan"
        },
        {
            "question": "147.\u2018White Knight Corps\u2019 is headquartered in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Punjab",
                "Sikkim",
                "Jammu and Kashmir",
                "Rajasthan"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Jammu and Kashmir"
        },
        {
            "question": "148.Which country has set up the \u2018Palli Karma Sahayak Foundation (PKSF)\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Bangladesh",
                "Myanmar",
                "Nepal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Bangladesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "149.Dr Jayant V. Narlikar, who was seen in the news recently, is associated with which profession?",
            "options": [
                "Historian",
                "Astronomer",
                "Scientist",
                "Virologist"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Astronomer"
        },
        {
            "question": "150.The World Bank has proposed a funding of 165 million USD for \u2018KERA\u2019 Program of which state?",
            "options": [
                "Karnataka",
                "Kerala",
                "Andhra Pradesh",
                "Rajasthan"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Kerala"
        }
    ]
}